# Kartiki Sahu

# Lead Software Engineer

Solution-driven professional excelling in the highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. I have **6+ years** of experience in developing pixel-perfect UI using JavaScript, NodeJs, Angular, Polymer, Twitter Bootstrap, HTML, SCSS, & jQuery

	+91	9860514359 /	7276769618
ы		700031 13337	, 2, 0, 0,00

kartikis26@gmail.com

github.com/kartiki-sahu

linkedin.com/in/kartikisahu

# Skills

Language: JavaScript, Node.js, Python Framework: Angular, Polymer, React, Django

Database: MongoDB Cloud: Cloudfoundary and GE's Predix

Others: HTML, CSS, Twitter bootstrap, Jquery

# Work Experience

## **Lead Software Engineer**

**VMware** 

July 2020 - Present

- Building a solution to facilitate sales team endorse their products. Designing and Developing pixel-perfect, reusable web-components.
- · Added Server-side Pagination, caching and O-Auth
- Using Angular 11, Node Js, typescript, Clarity, HTML and SCSS
- Leading a team of 2+ Associates

## **Lead Software Engineer**

T-Mobile

Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

- Build Solution to automate QA's Regression, Progression & Sanity test cases. Empowered them to schedule these
  test cases and displayed intutive reports covering failure reason, snapshots and video
- Designed and Developed a dynamic theme-based dashboard and it's architecture. Developed pixel-perfect, reusable web-components
- Wrote unit test cases and quality controlled using Sonarqube
- Used Angular 9, Node JS, SCSS, Twitter Bootstrap, HTML and SCSS
- Lead team of 3+ associates

### **Senior Software Engineer**

AT&T

July 2019 - Dec 2019

- Built Solution to manage IoT devices
- Planned and engineered RESTful web services in NodeJS and Python
- Handled end to end workflow for UI project
- Used Angular 8, Python, Node JS, Twitter Bootstrap, HTML and SCSS

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

**General Electrics** 

Mar 2016 - May 2019

- Built cutting edge IoT solutions for Current division of GE. Designed and developed consumer-facing UI
  applications. Created re-usable UI web-components. <a href="Here">Here</a> is a video demonstrating entire work
- Developed various Node parsers to read high volume excel data and convert it to application consumable JSON
- Designed API contract in Node Js, implemented caching and server-side pagination in Polymer
- Deployed application on PaaS platforms like Cloud Foundry and Predix
- Used Polymer, Node Js, HTML and CSS

## **Software Engineer**

Crowdera

Jun 2014 - Jan 2016

- Developed web applications using Groovy, Grails, Bootstrap 3, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery and AJAX
- 3
- Implemented 2 payment gateway FirstGiving and PayPal along with Gmail Google API
- Designed and developed custom URL shortener
- Determined operational feasibility by analyzing problem definition, requirements and proposed solution
- Drove operational improvements which resulted in savings and improved profit margins
- Used Groovy, Grails, GSP, Twitter Bootstrap, HTML and CSS

# **Work History**

**Lead Software Engineer** 

Globallogic India Pvt. Ltd

July 2019 - present

**Senior Software Engineer** 

InfoCepts Technologies

Mar 2016 - May 2019

# **Software Engineer**

Crowdera

Jun 2014 - Jan 2016

# Education

## **Bachelor of Engineering Specilization in Information Technology**

Karamveer Dadasaheb Kannamwar College of Engineering, Nagpur University Jun 2010 - May 2014

# Volunteering Experience

### Coding Bootcamp instructor | InfoCepts | 2018 - 2019

- HTML & CSS for beginners
- JavaScript for beginners

## CSR Activities | InfoCepts | 2016 - 2019

- Mentor and Guardian of Chinteshwar School
- Child Development activity in BGS Girls High School, Hope Child Development Centre Chankapur, Dayaram
- Wade High School
- Tree Plantation
- Diwali distribute happiness

## Certified Listener | 7 Cups | 2020 - Present

• Being a certified listener I listen to individual's grievance and try to console them

# Honour and Awards

#### Spot Award | GlobalLogic | Aug - 2019

For developing a complex dashboard before time and guiding team

### Project Transform Award | InfoCepts | Aug - 2019

- Fought across InfoCepts Globe
- Awarded for being consistent and marking stories back to back

#### Synergy Team Award | InfoCepts Technologies | 2017 - 2019

- Being awarded thrice for turning out things quickly
- Marking success story back to back

#### Star Award | InfoCepts Technologies | 2017 - 2019

- Being awarded twice by this honour for being instrumental in the project and developing complex architecture
- Vital member of team for developing user friendly screens with minimal time